<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>react-native-examples on Useful NodeJS Tricks, JavaScript Tips, Tricks and Best Practices</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/categories/react-native-examples/</link><description>Recent content in react-native-examples on Useful NodeJS Tricks, JavaScript Tips, Tricks and Best Practices</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 08:51:55 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nextjsvietnam.com/categories/react-native-examples/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[React Native Examples] Setup Working Place for React Native Developer</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/react-native-examples-setup-working-place-for-react-native-developer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 08:51:55 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/react-native-examples-setup-working-place-for-react-native-developer/</guid><description>Forewords What is React Native? Technical View Views JSX Components are compiled to Native Views, not the javascript logic code.
Components are compiled
What about JS Logic Code? Expo CLI vs React Native CLI Conclusion:
You can start with expo cli because of easy working flow and less setup With expo, you can test with native functions like camera with devices more easier. You can always switch from expo cli to react native cli just by using &amp;ldquo;eject&amp;rdquo; With React Native CLI setup, you can mix between js code and platform native code, such as: kotline or swift React Natve CLI required more setup Setup working environment Install Android Studio Create new React Native project with expo VSCode Extension and setup Debug Setup Android Studio To publish your app for testing Setup Android Studio To publish your app for production Install Android Studio Download the latest Android Studio version at official link Then you can create a new virtual device(which will be used to run for testing your React Native app) And you get this virtual device on your screen</description></item></channel></rss>