<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>systemdesign on Useful NodeJS Tricks, JavaScript Tips, Tricks and Best Practices</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/categories/systemdesign/</link><description>Recent content in systemdesign on Useful NodeJS Tricks, JavaScript Tips, Tricks and Best Practices</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 22:15:06 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nextjsvietnam.com/categories/systemdesign/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Aws Hand on Labs</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-hand-on-labs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 22:15:06 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-hand-on-labs/</guid><description>Types of labs Using EC2 Roles and Instance Profiles in AWS Architecture
Scenario
You are responsible for ensuring your applications hosted in Amazon EC2 are able to securely access other AWS services. Credentials need to be rotated regularly to minimize the adverse impact of a security breach. You want to minimize the time it takes to manage these credentials. AWS IAM roles provide the ability to automatically grant instances temporary credentials without the need for manual management.</description></item><item><title>Learn Aws Practitioner Level the Right Way</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/learn-aws-practitioner-level-the-right-way/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 08:46:51 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/learn-aws-practitioner-level-the-right-way/</guid><description>Roadmap Introduction to AWS Services Cloud concepts Amazon EC2 AWS Compute Services 1. Introduction to AWS Services What is cloud computing? Pay as you go model? The benefits of cloud computing? Introduction of AWS Services Practice Exams 1.1. What is cloud computing? A solution to provide IT resources through internet
1.2. Summary AWS Services:
Solution to provide IT resources through internet Provide solutions for your business through internet: other aws services The benefits of Cloud Computing(costs, time, speed and agility) Deployment model: cloud-based, on-premises(private cloud), hybrid(cloud-based + on-premises) Practition Level</description></item><item><title>The Difference Between Monolithic and Microservices Architecture</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/the-difference-between-monolithic-and-microservices-architecture/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 15:52:14 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/the-difference-between-monolithic-and-microservices-architecture/</guid><description>Monolith advantages and drawbacks A monolithic architecture is a traditional software development model that uses one code base to perform multiple business functions.
Advantages of Monolithic Architecture Simplicity of development : all source code is located in one place which can be quickly understood.
Simplicity of debugging : The debugging process is simple because all code is located in one place. You can easily follow the flow of a request and find an issue.</description></item><item><title>UML Use Case Diagram Cheatsheet</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/uml-use-case-diagram-cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 09:39:41 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/uml-use-case-diagram-cheatsheet/</guid><description>Four main characteristics of Use Case Diagrams:
1. Systems
A system is whatever you&amp;rsquo;re developing. It could be a website, a software component, a business process, an app, or any number of other things. You represent a system with a rectangle. 2. Actors
An actor is going to be someone or something that uses our system to achieve a goal, and they&amp;rsquo;re represented by a stick figure.</description></item><item><title>The Meaning of Software Architecture</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/the-meaning-of-software-architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 10:19:02 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/the-meaning-of-software-architecture/</guid><description>What makes up a software architecture? Software Architecture of a program or computing system is the structure of structures of the system, which comprise software elements, the externally visible properties of those elements, and the relationships between them.
Nowadays, software development methodologies focus on developing highly adaptive software, can be easily changed over time, resulting in less of a need for rigid, upfront planning. However, software architecture still consists of early design decisions that can be difficult to change later.</description></item><item><title>Domain Driven Design trong 30 giây</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/domain-driven-design-trong-30-giay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 13:47:24 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/domain-driven-design-trong-30-giay/</guid><description>Trong một mô hình thiết kế phần mềm truyền thống, khi chúng ta nhận 1 dự án, việc đầu tiên là phân tích các nghiệp vụ từ yêu cầu phần mềm, thu thập dữ liệu, và bắt đầu bằng việc thiết kế cơ sở dữ liệu, sau đó mới phân tách thành các chức năng cho các thành viên trong dự án để làm việc.
Đôi khi chúng ta sẽ nhận thấy rằng, trong mã nguồn, phần logic nghiệp vụ, đôi khi xen kẽ chung với cả phần giao diện người dùng hay thậm chí có cả kết nối database trong đó.</description></item><item><title>Learn Aws Solution Architect Associate the Fastest Way</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/learn-aws-solution-architect-associate-the-fastest-way/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 09:40:09 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/learn-aws-solution-architect-associate-the-fastest-way/</guid><description>The main topics will be discussed in this article:
Hands-on practice tutorials The architecture patterns : real cases example Tools AWS Policy Generator I.Overview AWS provide us &amp;ldquo;The SAA-C03 Exam&amp;rdquo;, if you can pass the exam, you will get this certificate
AWS Solution Architect - Associate
About the exam:
Level : Associate Length: 130 minutes Format: 65 questions Cost : $150 USD Delivery Method : Testing center or online Scoring: scaled score between 100 - 1000.</description></item><item><title>System Design Head First</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/system-design-head-first/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 11:39:43 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/system-design-head-first/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>