<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>aws on Useful NodeJS Tricks, JavaScript Tips, Tricks and Best Practices</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/categories/aws/</link><description>Recent content in aws on Useful NodeJS Tricks, JavaScript Tips, Tricks and Best Practices</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 14:40:26 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nextjsvietnam.com/categories/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Aws Series Automation</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-series-automation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 14:40:26 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-series-automation/</guid><description>Automation Benefit:
Time Consistency Security CloudFormation Allows you to provision resources quickly and consistently, and manage them throughout their lifecycles, by treating infrastructure as code. Elastic Beanstalk Easy-to-use all in one service for deploying and scaling web applications and services developed with a variety of supported languages System Manager Gives you the ability to easily patch, update, manage and configure your EC2 instances along with on-premise architecture.</description></item><item><title>Aws Series Security</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-series-security/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:12:10 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-series-security/</guid><description>DDos Attack SYN Floods Attack SYN Flood use TCP 3-Way Handshake to attack the servers
Some concepts
SYN(Synchronize Sequence Number) ACK(Acknowledgement) TCP 3-Way Handshake Process
How SYN floods attack work?
Uses the built-in patience of the TCP stacks to overwhelm a server by sending a large number of SYN packets and then ignoring the SYN-ACKs returned by the server. This causes the server to use up resources waiting for a set of amount time for the anticipated ACK that should come from a legitimate client.</description></item><item><title>Aws Series Serverless Computing</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-series-serverless-computing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 15:49:26 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-series-serverless-computing/</guid><description>AWS Lambda Serverless compute service that lets you run code without provisioning or managing the underlying servers. So you can focus on code, not the servers! Automated scaling
Lambda Main features Free tier 1M requests and 400K GBs of compute per month Integrates with numerous AWS services: S3, DynamoDB, EventBridge, SQS/SNS, and Kinenis CloudWatch for Logging Set memories requirement as needed, up to 10,240 MB! CPU scales with memory Execution Length: short-term executions, limit time is 900s(15mins).</description></item><item><title>Aws Series Big Data</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-series-big-data/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 19:06:05 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-series-big-data/</guid><description>The 3Vs of Big Data Volume
Ranges from terabytes to petabytes of data Variety
Includes data from a wide range of sources and formats Velocity
Data needs to be collected, stored, processed, and analyzed within a short period of time Amazon Redshift Fully managed, petabyte-scale data warehouse service in cloud It&amp;rsquo;s a very large relational database traditional used in big data applications.</description></item><item><title>Aws Series Decoupling Workflows</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-series-decoupling-workflows/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 23:48:50 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-series-decoupling-workflows/</guid><description>The issue with tight coupling The solution : loose coupling Simple Queue Service(SQS) SQS is fully managed message queuing service that enables you to decouple and scale microservices, distributed systems, and serverless applications. A message queue that allows asynchronous processing of work. One resource write a message to an SQS queue, and then another resource retrieve that messages from SQS Some important settings Delivery delay: default is 0, max value is 15 minutes Message size: up to 256KB of text in any format Encryption: messages are encrypted in transit by default, but you can add at-rest Message retention: default is 4 days, can be set between 1 minutes and 14 days.</description></item><item><title>Aws Series High Availability and Scaling</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-series-high-availability-and-scaling/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 09:31:02 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-series-high-availability-and-scaling/</guid><description>Vertical Scaling vs Horizontal Scaling Vertical Scaling Eg:
Increase your EC2 RAM Increase your EC2 CPU &amp;hellip; Horizontal Scaling Eg:
Add new EC2 Add new EC2 &amp;hellip; But we dont' only scale EC2, it should include other parts:
Database VPC AZ &amp;hellip; The 3W&amp;rsquo;s of Scaling What do we scale?
What sort of resource, we&amp;rsquo;re going to scale. How do we define template?</description></item><item><title>Aws Series Cloud Watch</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-series-cloud-watch/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 20:30:53 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-series-cloud-watch/</guid><description>CloudWatch is an monitoring and observability platform that was designed to give us insight into our AWS architecture. It allows us to monitor multiple levels of our applications and identify potential issues
CloudWatch Features System Metrics Application Metrics : information inside EC2 Alarms: Alarms us when something&amp;rsquo;s wrong Types of Metrics Application Monitoring Using CloudWatch Logs What do we do with our logs which comes from: EC2, RDS, LAMBDA, CloudTrail, On-Premises</description></item><item><title>Aws Series Elb</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-series-elb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 17:03:17 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-series-elb/</guid><description>Elastic Load Balancing
Automatically distributes incoming application traffic across multiple targets, such as Amazon EC Instances. 4 Diffrent Types of Load Balancers
Application Load Balancer: http/https traffic, operate at layer 7 (Intelligence) Network Load Balancer: operating at connection level (layer 4) on OSI Model (Performance) Gateway Load Balancers: operating at network level (layer 3 on OSI Model) (inline Virtual Appliance Load Balancing) Classic Load Balancers: http/https traffic, use layer 7 specific feature X-Forwarded, sticky session, classic/dev/test Load Balancer routes request only to the healthy instances</description></item><item><title>Aws Series Route 53</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-series-route-53/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 10:30:59 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-series-route-53/</guid><description>Route 53 is Amazon&amp;rsquo;s DNS service. It allows you to register domain names, create hosted zones, and manage and create DNS records
DNS operates on port 53 -&amp;gt; so that&amp;rsquo;s why it is called Route 53
SOA(Start of Authority) Record:
nslookup -q=soa jsbase.dev # Then Non-authoritative answer: jsbase.dev origin = izabella.ns.cloudflare.com mail addr = dns.cloudflare.com serial = 2324118412 refresh = 10000 retry = 2400 expire = 604800 minimum = 1800 NS(Name Server) Record: include IP of DNS Server and information about that domain</description></item><item><title>Aws Series Compute</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-series-compute/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 10:27:36 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-series-compute/</guid><description>3. Compute 3.1. EC2 VM but hosted on Amazon Infrastructure
3.1..1 Amazon EC2 Pricing Options: On Demand
Pay by the hour or the second, depend on instance type Short term Flexible Testing the water Reversed capacity:
Predictable usage Specific capacity requirement Pay upfront for 1 or 3 years Standard RIs - up to 72% off the on-demand price. Convertible RIs - 54% off the on-demand price.</description></item><item><title>Aws Series Networking</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-series-networking/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 10:22:54 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-series-networking/</guid><description>6. Networking 6.1. VPC Virtual Private Cloud Fully customized your network Create a hardward Virtual Private Network(VPN) connection between your data center and your AWS VPC. Logical data center in AWS Consists of: internet gateway, route tables, network access control lists, subnets, security groups 1 subnet is always in 1 Availability Zone (subnet can&amp;rsquo;t span into multiple AZs) Amazon IPV4 CIDR block size must be between /16 - /24 What can we do with VPC</description></item><item><title>Aws Hand on Labs</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-hand-on-labs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 22:15:06 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-hand-on-labs/</guid><description>Types of labs Using EC2 Roles and Instance Profiles in AWS Architecture
Scenario
You are responsible for ensuring your applications hosted in Amazon EC2 are able to securely access other AWS services. Credentials need to be rotated regularly to minimize the adverse impact of a security breach. You want to minimize the time it takes to manage these credentials. AWS IAM roles provide the ability to automatically grant instances temporary credentials without the need for manual management.</description></item><item><title>Learn Aws Practitioner Level the Right Way</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/learn-aws-practitioner-level-the-right-way/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 08:46:51 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/learn-aws-practitioner-level-the-right-way/</guid><description>Roadmap Introduction to AWS Services Cloud concepts Amazon EC2 AWS Compute Services 1. Introduction to AWS Services What is cloud computing? Pay as you go model? The benefits of cloud computing? Introduction of AWS Services Practice Exams 1.1. What is cloud computing? A solution to provide IT resources through internet
1.2. Summary AWS Services:
Solution to provide IT resources through internet Provide solutions for your business through internet: other aws services The benefits of Cloud Computing(costs, time, speed and agility) Deployment model: cloud-based, on-premises(private cloud), hybrid(cloud-based + on-premises) Practition Level</description></item><item><title>Learn Aws Solution Architect Associate the Fastest Way</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/learn-aws-solution-architect-associate-the-fastest-way/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 09:40:09 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/learn-aws-solution-architect-associate-the-fastest-way/</guid><description>The main topics will be discussed in this article:
Hands-on practice tutorials The architecture patterns : real cases example Tools AWS Policy Generator AWS CLI AWS EBS Volume Types I.Overview AWS provide us &amp;ldquo;The SAA-C03 Exam&amp;rdquo;, if you can pass the exam, you will get this certificate
AWS Solution Architect - Associate
About the exam:
Level : Associate Length: 130 minutes Format: 65 questions Cost : $150 USD Delivery Method : Testing center or online Scoring: scaled score between 100 - 1000.</description></item></channel></rss>