<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>aws on Useful NodeJS Tricks, JavaScript Tips, Tricks and Best Practices</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/categories/aws/</link><description>Recent content in aws on Useful NodeJS Tricks, JavaScript Tips, Tricks and Best Practices</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 22:15:06 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nextjsvietnam.com/categories/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Aws Hand on Labs</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-hand-on-labs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 22:15:06 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/aws-hand-on-labs/</guid><description>Types of labs Using EC2 Roles and Instance Profiles in AWS Architecture
Scenario
You are responsible for ensuring your applications hosted in Amazon EC2 are able to securely access other AWS services. Credentials need to be rotated regularly to minimize the adverse impact of a security breach. You want to minimize the time it takes to manage these credentials. AWS IAM roles provide the ability to automatically grant instances temporary credentials without the need for manual management.</description></item><item><title>Learn Aws Practitioner Level the Right Way</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/learn-aws-practitioner-level-the-right-way/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 08:46:51 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/learn-aws-practitioner-level-the-right-way/</guid><description>Roadmap Introduction to AWS Services Cloud concepts Amazon EC2 AWS Compute Services 1. Introduction to AWS Services What is cloud computing? Pay as you go model? The benefits of cloud computing? Introduction of AWS Services Practice Exams 1.1. What is cloud computing? A solution to provide IT resources through internet
1.2. Summary AWS Services:
Solution to provide IT resources through internet Provide solutions for your business through internet: other aws services The benefits of Cloud Computing(costs, time, speed and agility) Deployment model: cloud-based, on-premises(private cloud), hybrid(cloud-based + on-premises) Practition Level</description></item><item><title>Learn Aws Solution Architect Associate the Fastest Way</title><link>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/learn-aws-solution-architect-associate-the-fastest-way/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 09:40:09 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nextjsvietnam.com/post/learn-aws-solution-architect-associate-the-fastest-way/</guid><description>The main topics will be discussed in this article:
Hands-on practice tutorials The architecture patterns : real cases example Tools AWS Policy Generator AWS CLI AWS EBS Volume Types I.Overview AWS provide us &amp;ldquo;The SAA-C03 Exam&amp;rdquo;, if you can pass the exam, you will get this certificate
AWS Solution Architect - Associate
About the exam:
Level : Associate Length: 130 minutes Format: 65 questions Cost : $150 USD Delivery Method : Testing center or online Scoring: scaled score between 100 - 1000.</description></item></channel></rss>